You guys can grab a seat.
Well, that was better than any sermon I'm gonna preach,
so we'll keep it short this morning.
How's that sound?
I think I owe you guys like 20 minutes too
because I brought a guest speaker in last week
and, you know, he hasn't preached in a while,
so hour, 10 minutes, it's fine, it's fine.
We had a good time, didn't we?
We had a good time, we had a time of prayer at the end,
and I do wanna remind you,
I know some of you were uncomfortable
with the time of prayer at the end,
breaking into small groups in the middle of a church service.
Again, if that made you uncomfortable,
our tech team is always looking for volunteers.
You can hide.
And if that just, like, lit you up and excited you,
our prayer team is always looking for volunteers.
So, you know, come see me and we'll talk about it.
It'll be great.
So we have been in a series
through everyone's favorite book of the Bible,
the book of Revelation, correct?
Hopefully by now it is becoming
one of your favorite books of the Bible.
It's one that I have avoided for much of my life
in ministry because it is often misunderstood
and the interpretation is often focused on
maybe a secondary, third, not a primary goal of the book.
We've said so far that the groundwork
of the book of Revelation is not a puzzle to decode.
It isn't primarily about future events.
It is about the revealing of Jesus Christ,
how he is currently present, ruling, and reigning.
He sounds like a roaring lion
and he looks like a slain lamb.
He is sitting on the throne.
And what we did this morning in worship
is we joined in the heavenly throne room
that has been, will, and continue to worship Jesus.
The book of Revelation is meant
to encourage struggling churches.
It's written to real people
who understood the imagery better
than we're gonna understand the imagery.
It was meant to encourage churches
who are struggling through persecution
to challenge rebellious churches,
to wake up, to invite them to repent,
to wake up stagnant churches.
And like Pastor Sam said last week,
to invite people who are outside the church
to see the hardship of this world
as an invitation to God
to repent and trust him and his story.
Sam talked about some of the wrath
that we experience some of the suffering
and pain that we experience on earth
is a loving father doing everything he can
to get our attention to stop us
from harming ourselves and those around us.
What length would you not go
to stop someone you love
from causing irreparable harm
to themselves or others?
And that is the verse, John 3, 16,
for God so loved the world
that he gave his only son.
And today, John's gonna break from the drama
we've had at the heavenly throne room.
We hear the lion and we see the lamb
and the lamb is the only one
who is worthy to break the seals.
He begins to break seven seals
at the end of the seventh seal.
Seven trumpets get blown.
And we have a break here in the action
where John kind of stops
from this unfolding drama
of the seven seals being broken.
And he zooms out for us.
And I think what he's doing
is he's giving us an anchoring point
so that we don't lose sight
of the story of God.
I think we all need regular reminders
of where we're at in the story
and how God is inviting us to participate.
And so today, that's our goal
to kind of zoom out
from all of the scary images, right?
The unfolding drama
of God's wrath being revealed
and Jesus overcoming sin and death.
And he's just gonna give us
a picture of where we're at in the story.
Today, my goal is for this
to be a shorter sermon, like I said.
And what I wanna do
is focus on the spiritual realities
that we just witnessed
in the baptismal waters.
And we're gonna end with communion
and a focus on the spiritual realities
of communion
and how we see both of those things
being played out
in Revelation chapter 12
in God's story.
Sound good?
It's gonna have to sound good
because it's in my notes.
There we are.
All right.
That's the worst pastor joke ever,
but sometimes you just gotta keep
going back to the classics.
All right.
Jesus, Father, Holy Spirit,
we give you thanks
for what we were able
to participate in this morning
as we witnessed young people
pass through the waters of chaos
and out the other side
to resurrected life.
And God, those of us
who have been following Jesus
for any time at all
know that it isn't always promised land
immediately on the other side
of baptismal waters.
Oftentimes, it's wandering
in the wilderness.
It's suffering.
It's difficulty.
And that's the importance of us
as a family,
supporting people
as they walk with you.
And so give us eyes to see
and hands to participate
in the discipleship process
of those who are following you
for the first time today.
Give us just wisdom
as we read through this text
and help us to see
what we need to see.
Holy Spirit,
would you speak your words?
And when I say the words
that are mine,
would you correct them
in the ears of the hearer?
Just as Peter's first sermon
was heard by each individual
in their own language,
may each individual
in this room
hear the words
that you need them
to hear today.
For your glory,
for our good,
and for the good
of our neighbor.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Not trying to age anybody,
but how many of you remember
when the movie
The Breakfast Club came out?
All right.
Good chunk of you, right?
Obviously, I wasn't around
when it came out.
You wouldn't be able to tell
by my hairline,
but I wasn't.
But I really loved the movie,
and I love how trailers
used to work in the 80s and 90s.
Some of you,
I don't know if any of you
are into like movie trailers,
but like when I was thinking
about my sermon,
I was thinking about movie trailers
in the 80s and 90s
because nowadays,
it's just like fast-paced clips.
We got short attention spans.
It's just like hitting us
in the face
and then the trailer's over.
But back in the day,
they used to introduce you
to the characters,
even the actors
who played the characters,
and the clips would just kind of
give you a general idea
of the plot,
the tension,
the potential resolution.
The Breakfast Club
is one of the best examples of this.
They even kind of,
as they introduce each character,
they say the brains,
the beauty,
the jock,
the rebel,
the recluse, right?
Like they're introducing you
to these characters
so that before you even
step into the theater,
you know the main characters
in the movie,
and you kind of get a gist
of what the general plot is,
and maybe even what some
of the potential resolution
might be.
And most of the time
when we see a trailer
like this,
stories,
the way stories function,
they often follow
a general kind of plot line
and resolution,
and we're often familiar enough
with characters like this
and stories like this
that before we even step
into the theaters,
we kind of know
what to expect.
And I think
that this is really
how Revelation 12
is functioning
in John's unfolding drama,
is it's almost a trailer
for the unified story
of God in the Scripture.
He's introducing us
to three main characters
that continue to play a part
in God's unfolding drama
from literally Genesis 1
to the end of Revelation.
And I need us to hear
that the Bible tells
one unified story.
Because I often grow up
studying the books
and I've been told,
you know,
that the Bible
is 66 different books,
it's a library
of different genres
and literatures,
and that's all true
and it's important
for how we interpret
the Scriptures.
But sometimes we get
so focused on how
each individual book functions
that we lose sight
that the book
is building off
of the story,
that God is telling
one story
from Genesis 1
to Revelation 22.
And so what we have here
in Revelation 12
is a trailer
for that story
and how it's been unfolding
and how it will continue
to unfold
and where we are at
in the story.
And I think
that is gonna give us
an invitation
to think about
how we should participate
in light of where
we're at
in the story.
And at this point
in Revelation,
we've talked about
how we're between
the inaugurated
and consummated
kingdom of God,
that Jesus has
accomplished
the final victory
through his death,
burial,
resurrection,
and ascension.
This is the most important
part of the book
of Revelation
that we cannot forget.
When we talk about
the gospel,
we often,
sometimes we end
at the cross,
other times we end
at the resurrection,
but rarely do you hear
anybody preach a gospel
that includes the ascension
and that it's very important
to understand
where we're at
in the story,
that there is a one
who sits on the throne
right now.
That we are a part
of a story
that is unfolding
where the victory
has already been won.
It has been,
the kingdom of God
has been inaugurated
and it is yet
to fully be consummated
but we are waiting
in this in-between
already,
not yet.
And the question
then becomes for us
when we find ourselves
at this part of the story,
maybe you find yourself
asking if Jesus
really defeated death
then why is there
so much suffering
all around me?
This is a fair question
to ask as many of us
go through the difficulties
and trials of this life
as we experience
the pangs of death
and sorrow.
We might ask ourselves,
okay,
if Jesus really is
who he said he is,
if he really did
what he said he did
then why is there
still so much suffering?
And John breaks
from the unfolding drama
to remind his readers
and ultimately us
of the overall story
we find ourselves
in,
the main characters
and how we're called
to faithfully participate.
And throughout,
I really want to land
on baptism and communion
and how that functions
in the story.
I think we put it up
on the slide,
the Christian life
only makes sense
if we understand the story
because if we don't
understand the story,
we'll find ourselves
asking those questions
like why is there
suffering all around us?
And we might end up
blaming God
for something that
isn't his fault at all.
So let's real quick
just read chapter 12
and I'd love for you
to just,
some of these images
and the storyline in 12
is a little bit easier
to understand
than some of the earlier images
that we've read.
It's still hard.
I'm not saying
you're gonna understand everything
but if you have any,
if you've grown up at all
with the Scriptures,
I want you to just try
and like maybe even
close your eyes
and just hear the story unfold
and maybe try
and make a couple connections
for yourself along the way,
okay?
Revelation 12,
starting in verse one,
and a great sign appeared
in heaven.
A woman clothed with the sun
with the moon under her feet
and on her head
a crown of 12 stars.
She was pregnant
and was crying out
in birth pains
and the agony of giving birth
and another sign
appeared in heaven.
Behold,
a great red dragon
with seven heads
and 10 horns on his head,
seven diadems.
His tail swept down
a third of the stars of heaven
and cast them to the earth
and the dragon stood
before the woman
who was about to give birth
so that she bore her child.
When she bore her child,
he might devour it.
She gave birth
to a male child,
one to rule all the nations
with a rod of iron,
but her child was caught up
to God and to his throne
and the woman fled
into the wilderness
where she had a place
prepared by God
in which she is to be nourished
1,260 days.
Now war arose in heaven.
Michael and his angels
fighting against the dragon
and the dragon
and his angels fought back,
but he was defeated.
There was no longer
any place for them in heaven
and the great dragon was,
look at your neighbor
and say,
thrown down.
It's gonna repeat,
so get ready.
We're gonna do that again.
That ancient serpent
who was called the devil
and Satan,
the deceiver of the whole world,
he was thrown down
to the earth
and his angels
were thrown down with him.
And I heard a loud voice
in heaven saying,
now salvation
and the power
and the kingdom of God
and the authority of Christ
has come.
For the accuser
of our brothers
has been
broken out.
Who accuses them
day and night
before our God
and they have conquered him
by the blood
of the lamb
and the word
of their testimony
for they love
not their lives
even unto death.
Therefore rejoice,
O heavens,
and you who dwell in them,
but woe to you,
O earth
and sea
for the devil
has come down
to you
in great wrath
because he knows
his time is short.
And when the dragon
saw that he had been
thrown down to the earth,
he pursued the woman
who had given birth
to the male child,
but the woman
was given two wings
of a great eagle
so that she might fly
from the serpent
into the wilderness
to the place
where she is to be nourished
for time
and times
and half a time.
The serpent poured water
like river
out of his mouth
after the woman
to sweep her away
with a flood,
but the earth came
to help the woman
and the earth
opened its mouth
and swallowed up the river
that the dragon
had poured from his mouth.
Then the dragon
became furious
with the woman
and went off
to make war
on the rest
of her offspring,
on those who keep
the commandments of God
and hold to their testimony
of Jesus.
And he stood
on the sand
of the sea.
So hopefully
some of the details
in these signs
that John sees
are not totally
unfamiliar to you.
Hopefully they're triggering
some things
in your mind
that you may have read
in the Scriptures
and other places.
There's three main characters
that John focuses on
in this chapter.
There's a woman,
a child,
and a dragon.
Fun stuff, right?
Are we in Harry Potter
or are we in the Bible?
Yes.
I got a buddy
who wrote a really good book
about how Harry Potter
essentially is the gospel.
but that's another time.
Good writers steal
from the best writer, okay?
That's all I'm saying.
All right.
At first reading,
it sounds an awful lot
like the Christmas story.
And that's because
in one sense
it is the Christmas story.
The woman sounds
a lot like Mary.
She's pregnant.
The devil,
the dragon,
sounds a lot like
King Herod
trying to have
all of the babies
under two years old
killed
so that another king
who was born,
who was prophesied about,
might not come
to fruition.
Interesting here
that the dragon
is working
through a political leader.
I'm just gonna put that
on the table
and move
because it's a short sermon,
right?
Okay.
And then obviously
the baby,
the ruler of all nations
with a rod iron.
We're talking about
Jesus here.
However,
I think if we just
think about it
as a Christmas story,
it's a bit too small
for what John
has in mind.
John's vision
of Mary
and her
being clothed
with the sun,
the moon under her feet
and the crown
of 12 stars.
This resembles
a dream
that Joseph has
in Genesis chapter 36,
I believe,
or 37,
somewhere around there.
And in that dream
and vision,
the woman represents
the people of God,
the faithful Israelites.
And so I think
if we just make
this image
one version
of the story,
we lose sight
of the fact
that it is
a vision
of the story
unfolding
from literally
the beginning
in Genesis 1
all the way through.
That this is
a repeated
story being told.
It's referring to,
sounds like
the nation of Israel
in Genesis 37.
It sounds like
Eve
in the garden,
a woman
who is told
that she would
bring forth
a child,
the seed
who would crush
the head
of a
serpent,
right?
And what happens
in that story
is a snake
also could be
dragon,
deceives
the woman
to try and delay
the process
of the child
coming.
Are we picking up
on how the Bible
is one unified story
from the very beginning
that this is a story
that gets repeated
and unfolded,
all moving towards
the culmination
of the one child,
the seed
of the woman
who would rule
the nations
with a rod
of iron
being born.
This is the story
of God
being told
on repeat.
God is partnering
with humanity
to bring order
out of chaos
while the dragon
desperately tries
to stop him.
This
is the movie trailer
for the story
of God
for the entire
biblical narrative.
God
partnering
with people
of faith
to bring
about the
seed
of the woman
who came
at the right
time
to crush
the head
of the serpent.
The serpent
will fight back
but the resurrection
and ascension
of Jesus
shows us
that God's
ultimate redemption
plan has been
set into motion
and as we read
he has been
thrown down.
He knows
that his time
is limited
and there is
nothing
that he can do
to stop
the process.
I love
the end
of verse 12
he knows
that his time
is short
which leads
us back
to the question
if Jesus
really has
the victory
that he said
he has
if he really
did raise
from the dead
and ascend
to heaven
on his throne
then why
is there
so much
suffering
and pain
and the reality
is it's
because there
is a dying
flailing
dragon
that has been
thrown down
to earth
and he is
doing whatever
he can
with the last
little bit
of time
that he can
to ruin
God's plan
that ultimately
will be fulfilled
and he can
do nothing
about it.
There is
this exhibit
at the
Discovery Museum
which I spend
a lot of time
at nowadays
it's awesome
it's behind
a plexiglass
wall
it's this rail
system
and there's
certain things
you can do
with balls
and you can
trigger balls
to start
down the rails
and once you
let the ball
go
there's nothing
that you can
do to stop
it
it's going
to go
to the next
spot
to trigger
the next
thing
to trigger
the next
thing
to trigger
the next
thing
once you
start it
there's
nothing
that can
stop it
and as I
was thinking
about this
sermon
I think
that's such
a helpful
illustration
of where
we're at
in the story
the ascension
of Jesus
seated on the
throne
breaking the
seven seals
of the redemptive
story of God
the process
has begun
and there is
nothing that
Satan can do
to stop it
verse 5
is literally
a summary
of everything
that happened
in Matthew
Mark
Luke
and John
and you'll
miss it
if you're not
paying attention
he says
she gave birth
the woman
gave birth
to a male
child
one to rule
all the nations
with a rod
iron
but her child
was caught
up to God
and to his throne
John's not wasting
any time on the
details because
we've already got
those recorded
Matthew
Mark
Luke
and John
this is
Jesus
the son
of God
living a perfect
life
dying in our
place
for our sins
raising from
the dead
and ascending
into heaven
to sit
on the throne
where he will
rule all the
nations with a rod
of iron
he is our
good shepherd
which leads us
to our next
question
after who are
the characters
and what is
the overall
storyline
we should
ask the
question
how am I
invited to
participate
in this story
until Christ
returns
the decisive battle
has been won
the dragon
has been
thank you
there we go
you guys are
awesome
other
the Greek
can literally
mean bounced
he's been
bounced
out of
heaven
evacuated
Jesus
has ascended
to his
rightful
throne
but like I
said at the
beginning
if this is
where we're
at in the
story
why is
there so
much
suffering
and pain
all around
us
oftentimes
suffering
causes us
to think
that God
might not
be real
that he
isn't
active
or at
least
he
isn't
good
but I
think
what John
is doing
here for
us
is
he's
reframing
our
suffering
and he's
saying
that suffering
actually proves
that God
is real
and he
has
accomplished
what he
set out
to do
that there
is a
flailing
dragon
on limited
borrowed
time
and he
knows it
and he's
desperately
thrashing
even though
he will soon
be defeated
he can still
cause
damage
the battle
has been
won
but the
suffering
persists
because the
enemy knows
he has
lost
again
another
silly
illustration
for you
but my
family
especially
on Marissa's
side
they love
to play
board games
card games
strategy games
all the
things
I like
it too
but here's
the thing
I don't
win very
often
and I
don't
like that
so there's
this thing
that happens
in a
strategy game
when there's
a moment
in time
usually about
halfway
through the
game
where I
realize
I'm
not
going
to win
and the
only
thing
I
can
do
to
continue
feel
like
I'm
participating
in the
story
is
just
try
to
make
the
person
that
is
winning
lose
because
at least
there's
still
some
juices
flowing
there
right
I'm
still
having
a little
bit
of
fun
there's
still
a little
bit
of
stake
in
the
game
and
ultimately
I
think
this
is
what
we're
seeing
here
in
Revelation
the
enemy
has
lost
and he
knows
it
notice
now
we're
gonna
get
to
baptism
and
communion
notice
what
the
serpent's
weapon
is
as
he's
thrown
down
the
serpent
poured
water
like a
river
out
of
his
mouth
after
the
woman
to
sweep
her
away
with
a
flood
again
this
should
be
triggering
if
it's
not
that's
okay
we're
not
often
conditioned
to
read
the
Bible
like
this
but
should
be
triggering
some
things
in
our
mind
about
how
water
has
played
a
pivotal
role
in
the
salvation
story
of
God's
people
throughout
history
baptism
happens
at the
beginning
of a
Christian's
journey
it's
an
embodiment
of the
faith
they have
in
God's
story
and
throughout
God's
story
water
plays
a
key
role
in
God's
salvation
plan
it is
a
symbol
in
the
old
covenant
in
the
old
testament
the
imagination
of
the
old
testament
readers
water
is
a
symbol
of
chaos
and
death
I
mean
water
is
powerful
and
these
people
live
off
of
the
water
and
they
realize
that
things
can
turn
in
an
instant
and
they
could
be
killed
or
destroyed
in
the
psalms
water
is
often
used
like
chaos
and
the
dragon
leviathan
these
demonic
characters
are
often
seen
coming
out
of
the
waters
in
the
imagination
of
the
old
testament
waters
represented
chaos
and
death
yet
throughout
the
story
God
shows
up
and
brings
his
people
through
their
salvation
will
be
experienced
in
Genesis
God
saves
Noah
and
his
family
in
the
ark
through
the
waters
of
chaos
and
death
in
Exodus
God
saves
Israel
through
the
waters
inviting
them
to
leave
their
old
identity
and
their
old
story
as
defined
by
Pharaoh
and
step
through
the
waters
of
chaos
to
salvation
on
the
other
side
and
so
what
we
pictured
this
morning
what
we
witnessed
in
the
waters
of
baptism
were
people
at
the
edge
of
the
waters
of
the
Red
Sea
looks
like
chaos
and
death
behind
them
is
their
old
identity
as
defined
by
whatever
worldly
system
they put
their
hope
in
what
other
identities
of
other
people
or
things
that
they
have
been
told
they
are
and
they
are
surrendering
themselves
to
the
waters
of
chaos
trusting
Jesus
to
bring
them
out
the
other
side
into
salvation
we're
embodying
the
story
of
God
from
the
beginning
all
the
way
through
this
is
the
story
God
repeatedly
brings
his
people
safely
through
the
waters
of
chaos
while
defeating
evil
forces
that
often
inhabit
them
this
is
what
baptism
embodies
born
on
the
wrong
side
of
the
chaos
waters
from
the
promised
land
all
of
us
stand
at
the
shore
of
the
red
sea
with
the
decision
we
can
go
back
to
Pharaoh
we
can
go
back
to
the
story
of
this
temporary
world
we
can
go
back
slaves
to
Pharaoh
and to
his
ideology
or
we
can
with
faith
step
into
the
waters
of
chaos
that
might
look
like
death
at
first
but
because
we
trust
the
story
ultimately
open up
for us
and
lead
to
life
and
salvation
it's
what
we
witnessed
people
leaving
behind
their
old
identities
their
old
worldviews
their
old
ideologies
and
saying
I'm
going
to
trust
God's
story
that
his
victory
has
been
won
and
that
even
though
suffering
and
pain
difficulty
exist
I'm
going
to
trust
that
his
story
is
the
one
that
wins
in
the
end
verse
through
really
is
this
picture
of how
we're
called
to
participate
where
we're
at
in
the
story
John
says
I heard
a loud
voice
in
heaven
saying
now
salvation
and
the
power
and
the
kingdom
of
God
and
the
authority
of
Christ
have
come
for
the
accuser
of
our
brothers
has
been
who
accuses
them
day
and
night
before
God
and
this
is
how
the
faithful
people
of
God
participate
in
the
story
they
have
conquered
him
by
the
blood
of
the
lamb
and
the
word
of
their
testimony
for
they
love
their
lives
not
even
unto
death
therefore
rejoice
oh
heavens
the
one
who
have
already
passed
through
they
see
what
we
know
to
be
true
through
the
revelation
of
Jesus
they
see
Jesus
sitting
on
the
throne
but
for
those
of
us
on
the
earth
it
says
woe
to
you
the
devil
has
come
down
and
life
is
going
to
be
hard
this
is
the
Christian
experience
oftentimes
when we
celebrate
baptism
it's
such a
celebratory
moment
that
we
forget
that
oftentimes
on
the
other
side
wandering
in
the
wilderness
because
life
is
hard
in
a
broken
world
trusting
Jesus
is
hard
when
there
is
an
accuser
who
seeks
to
deceive
believe
any
other
version
of
any
other
story
than
the
one
we've
trusted
in
the
waters
of
baptism
Jesus
his
story
is
our
story
the
Christian
life
only
makes
sense
if
we
understand
where
we're
at
in
the
story
and
I
think
that
Revelation
is
a
summary
of
this
unified
redemption
story
baptism
is
the
time
in
which
we
place
our
faith
we
put
our
trust
in
the
blood
of
the
lamb
it
is
the
moment
that
we
begin
to
conquer
when
we
place
our
faith
and
trust
in
the
blood
of
the
lamb
but
as
we
come
out
of
the
waters
into
salvation
and
new
identity
and
resurrected
life
there
is
an
ongoing
decision
to
be
made
it's
faith
and
faithfulness
faith
in
the
baptismal
waters
and
faithfulness
as we
continue
to
trust
the
story
even
when
things
get
hard
and
I
think
that's
what
communion
does
for
us
and
there's
a
reason
why
these
are
two
things
that
Jesus
commanded
his
church
to
do
because
they
embody
for
us
the
story
that
we're
in
they
remind
us
of
the
incredible
miraculous
salvation
that
God
brings
every
time
somebody
went
under
the
water
and
back
out
today
we
were
witnessing
an
exodus
level
miracle
a
red
sea
being
parted
decision
resurrected
life
we
were
witnessing
salvation
this
is
why
we
do
this
is
why
Jesus
invited
embody
the
story
because
the
Christian
story
isn't
just
in
our
head
it's
not
just
in
our
hearts
it's
in
our
hands
and
it's
in
our
feet
this
is
what
the
ordinances
are
about
we
do
things
tangibly
with
our
bodies
the
lamb
and
communion
is
this
ongoing
reminder
that
we
need
Jesus
to
sustain
us
in
the
wilderness
that
we
conquer
by
his
blood
and
the
only
way
that
we
can
have
the
strength
to
love
our
lives
not
unto
death
is
to
look
at
the
one
who
went
before
us
who
loved
his
life
not
unto
death
but
gave
his
life
so
that
we
might
be
saved
so
as
we
prepare
to take
communion
so
as we
prepare
to take
communion
we
think
about
the
story
and
again
back
to
the
text
right
days
we're
looking
at
three
and
a
half
years
we're
looking
at
months
again
we
should
be
thinking
Exodus
story
here
wilderness
wanderings
God
sustained
his
people
with
manna
bread
from
heaven
and
communion
becomes
this
regular
practice
that we
participate
in
that
sustains
us
in the
process
of learning
to love
our lives
not unto
death
because
I don't
know about
you
but
everything
in me
wants
to love
my
life
and
we
rehearse
the
story
of
Christ's
body
broken
for us
and his
blood
shed
for us
to
remind
ourselves
that
this
temporary
life
is not
worthy
of
loving
more
than
the
eternal
life
that
Jesus
has
offered
us
and
so
it is
this
opportunity
for us
to
week in
and week
out
regularly
remind
ourselves
that we
follow
a
savior
who
did
not
love
his
life
unto
death
and
he's
invited
us
to do
the
same
Christian
life
often
looks
like
laying
down
our
life
for
those
around
us
it's
about
ongoing
faithfulness
and
ongoing
dying
to
ourselves
it's the
we
witnessed it
at the
initial
baptism
laying
their
life
down
into the
grave
of
chaos
waters
and being
raised
to new
life
and that
is a
decision
that we
have to
keep
making
we
have to
keep
trusting
the
story
when
suffering
comes
and I
can
tell
you
that
when
suffering
comes
there's
a lot
of
temptation
a lot
of
accusation
from the
enemy
a lot
of
deception
from the
enemy
that tells
me
not
to
trust
the
story
because
the
story
doesn't
look
as
good
I've
been
told
it
looked
in
communion
coming
back
to
the
table
taking
the
body
of
Christ
broken
for
you
the
blood
of
Christ
shed
for
you
it
sustains
us
to
keep
participating
in
the
story
to
keep
trusting
in
the
story
trusting
that
the
story
is
good
God
invites
ordinary
people
to
participate
in
his
extraordinary
story
through
faith
in
Jesus
embodied
in
the
baptism
waters
and
faithfulness
to
Jesus
embodied
in
the
bread
and
the
cup
this
is
what
we're
doing
today
with
our
hands
with
our
bodies
we're
participating
in
the
story
we're
reminding
ourselves
that
the
enemy
has
been
thrown
down
and
he
will
cause
chaos
and
deception
death
but
his
time
is
short
and